– Contact ——

Thorntoneric115@gmail.com (865)-299-3416 Rochester, NY

Education –

Rochester Institute of Technology (BS/MS Electrical Engineering)-Anticipated Graduation: April 2024

Undergraduate GPA: 3.68
Dean's List: 2020 - 2023
Graduate GPA: 4.00

Thesis Title: "Explorations and

In Several Emerging Packaging
Technologies for Silicon Photonics"

——Publications—

Conference Paper, ECTC (abstract accepted, pending publication): "Packaged Tunable Single-Mode III-V Laser Integrated on a Silicon Photonic Integrated Chip using Photonic Wire Bonding"

Conference Paper, CELO
(abstract accepted, pending
publication): "Low-Loss Aluminum Nitride Waveguides in a 300
nm CMOS Foundry Process"

Certifications & Skills

Autodesk Fusion 360:
Certified User, 2018.
Programming:
C, C++, shell/bash, Python,
LabVIEW, MATLAB,
VHDL/Verilog, Perl, PHP.
Design Software: Fusion
360, Solidworks, Ki-Cad,
Altium Designer 23,
Cadence Virtuoso

—Portfolio of Work—

For detailed documentation of personal, professional, and academic projects see: https://eot105.github.io (Or scan QR Code below)



Eric Thornton

About

Passionate and motivated electrical engineer with extensive experience and interest in embedded systems, digital communication protocols, high and low-level software development, digital circuits, and photonics. Experienced with top-down design and skilled in understanding problems holistically. Professional exposure working in both the public and private sector, from startups to large firms. I believe that truly elegant solutions to meaningful problems emerge from teams composed of members that are skilled in a diverse set of fields, have rapport and respect for each other's efforts, understand the larger context of their work, and engage in continuous discussion and constructive debate of ideas.

Experience -

RIT Nanophotonics Group - Researcher (August 2022 - present)

- Ongoing development of MOSAICS (Multi Output Synchronized Adjustable Independent Current Sources) allowing an arbitrary number of nanoamp precision current sources to be controlled using a Python API to support the operation and testing of next generation photonic integrated circuits.
- Developed multiple process improvements and innovations related to the use of a state-of-the-art nanometer scale 3D printer used for heterogeneous integration of lasers and silicon photonic circuits, polymer MEMS structures, and micro-optics systems.

RIT Materials Science Department - Engineer (August 2022 - December 2022)

- Supported team researching light activated self healing polymers in engineering custom solutions to improve process consistency.
- Worked closely with lab technicians to understand current process shortcomings and developed a dual wavelength LED exposure system with precise intensity and exposure time control via a custom GUI.

Z-Axis, Inc - Electrical Engineering Intern. (August 2021 - August 2022)

- Top down, complete design (CAD, machining, electrical and software) of the "LED Poker", an electromagnetic actuator designed to automatically dislodge SMT LEDs from the vacuum pickup of a 3-axis LED sorting robot. Increased output of the machine from 50 to 300 LEDs/day, allowing the company to bid on higher volume, higher value orders with confidence of on-time delivery.
- Developed the Universal Test Fixture, a complex and application agnostic system
 designed to test power supplies with software defined test procedures, thus eliminating the need for bespoke test fixtures for each supply. Involved the development
 of a high-level user oriented GUI (written in python), and a low level communication
 protocol (parsed in C++).

SRC, Inc - Electrical Engineering Intern. (May 2021 - August 2021)

- Developed IPMI Parse and Control (IPAC) for the Agile Condor high performance edge computing system.
- IPAC extended the standard Intelligent Platform Management Interface (IPMI) to allow access to high level OS functions (e.g. IP addresses). This allowed richer diagnostics of networked client "slice" CPUs/GPUs from the host computer if the network interface was malfunctioning.

Oak Ridge National Laboratory, Unmanned Vehicles Development Group – Intern. (May 2019 – August 2019)

- Developed a novel packet protocol (BRNR-S.Bus) capable of transmitting low latency and fault tolerant telemetry data to unmanned vehicles over secure digital radio networks.
- Designed the hardware and firmware needed to implement this protocol and worked closely with other team members to integrate this hardware into the high level vehicle control system.